Leonard Szubowicz collection of Polish American Congress, District of Connecticut records CPAA.2012.01
Connecticut Polish American Archives
Leonard Szubowicz Collection of Polish American Congress, District of Connecticut records.
1971-1979
CPAA.2012.01
Connecticut Polish American Archives
0.5 Linear feet
The collection consists of Polish American Congress, District of Connecticut records for the years 1971 - 1979. It includes minutes, financial information, reports, newsletters and correspondence.
Biographical/Historical note
The Polish American Congress is a national civic and political organization that has represented the interests of Polish Americans since 1944. It is considered an “umbrella organization” federation consisting of over 3,000 Polish organizations and clubs that mutually support each other. It has over one million individual members and is organized into state divisions and chapters. Main objectives of the PAC were to struggle for a free and independent Poland, to provide necessary information on political situation in Poland, to encourage cooperation and support of Polish Americans for betterment of Polonia, and to combat derogatory information about Poles and Polish Americans in the media.
PAC District of Connecticut was very active organization, which in 1970's had very large membership base of individuals and organizations. Mr. Leonard Szubowicz was a treasurer of the organization and forwarded the records to CPAA in 1987.
Arrangement note
The material is arranged in chronological order.
Szubowicz, Leonard; Clippings.; Correspondence.; Minutes.; Pamphlets.; Polish American Congress; Polish American Congress. Connecticut Division; Polish Americans -- Connecticut
- PAC District of Connecticut: by-laws, history of PAC and PAC Conn. District., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- PAC District of Connecticut: Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- PAC District of Connecticut: correspondence with Governor Ella Grasso, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- PAC District of Connecticut- Quarterly Meetings, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- PAC District of Connecticut: Financial reports., 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- PAC District of Connecticut- Bulletins, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- PAC National Newsletter, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- PAC District of Connecticut- "The achievement of 1973, the challenge of the future" editorial by Michael A. Peszke (Box 1, Folder 8)
- PAC District of Connecticut: general announcements and flyers, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- PAC National: newspaper clippings, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- PAC District of Connecticut: Convention and meeting agendas, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- PAC District of Connecticut- Convention, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- PAC District of Connecticut: Polish Studies Program at CCSU and Mikolaj Kopernik Quintcentennial Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- PAC District of Connecticut- Pulaski Parade Committee, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- PAC District of Connecticut- The Bicentennial Programs, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 15, Folder 14)
- PAC District of Connecticut: List of officers, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- PAC District of Connecticut- Wisconsin Plan, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- PAC District of Connecticut: Report related to Katyn Memorial., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- PAC District of Connecticut: Millennium of Poland's Christianity, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- PAC District of Connecticut- Casimir Pulaski Launching, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- PAC District of Connecticut: anniversary booklets, programs, proclamations., 1965-1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- PAC District of Connecticut- ribbons for participants of national conventions, 1965-1978 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- PAC National - Reports and program of 10th National Convention in Philadelphia, PA, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)